League of Women Voters of Albany County; Records apap128
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Photographs and Scrapbooks, 1956-2000; 8; 2.61 cubic ft.
  The Photographs and Scrapbooks series includes photographs of LWVAC members and activities and scrapbooks kept by members. Although many of the photographs are unidentified the event at which the photographs were taken can usually be determined. There are many photographs taken during the Strengthening Women's Rights in the Newly Independent States Internship Program in 1995. There are also some news clippings of League members from local newspapers in the scrapbook dated 1961-1995, many of which were loose. The scrapbooks were disassembled for preservation reasons or photocopied depending upon their contents. The Government Unit Activities scrapbook topics include representative government, the President and Electoral College, constitutional conventions, sunset laws, as well as other topics. The Oversized scrapbook spanning the years 1970-1073 and 1977-1978 documents an array of League activities and interests including voter service, housing, welfare, the Albany elected school board campaign and its conflict with Mayor Erastus Corning, the county charter drive, the voter harassment case filed against James Ryan, as well as other issues. The Albany elected school board collage includes news clippings as well as a cartoon signed by the artist Hy Rosen. A small number of images are available for viewing online from the University at Albany Libraries' Digital Collections database.
  Existence and Location of Copies
  A small number of images are available for viewing online from the University at Albany Libraries' Digital Collections database.
  - Environment, Scrapbook, 1986-1989 (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 1)
  - "The Fight for an Elected School Board", Scrapbook, 1971 (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 2)
  - Government Unit Activities, Representative Government and the Electoral College, Scrapbook, 1970-1980 (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 3)
  - Government Unit Activities, Representative Government, Constitutional Convention and Sunset Laws, Scrapbook, 1970-1980 (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 4)
  - LWVNYS Convention, Photographs, ca. 1970s (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 5)
  - NIS Internship, Negatives, Undated (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 6)
  - Power the Vote Public Meeting, Photographs, from Series 2, 1996 (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 7)
  - President's Correspondence, Event and Participants Unknown, Photographs, from Series 1, 1996 (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 8)
  - Project Demokracia: Building Citizen Participation in Hungary Fellowship Program, Photographs and Itineraries, from Series 6, 1994 (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 9)
  - Redistricting, Scrapbook, 1965 (Box 36 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 10)
  - Scrapbook, 1952-1953 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook, 1952-1955 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1961-1995 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1966 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook, 1962-1967 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook, 1966-1969 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1970 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1993-1994 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1993-1997 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 9)
  - Strengthening Women's Rights in Newly Independent States, Photographs, from Series 6, ca. 1995-1996 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 10)
  - Strengthening Women's Rights in Newly Independent States and Halloween Party, Photographs, from Series 6, ca. 1995-1996 (Box 37 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 11)
  - Unidentified Event, Photographs, 1997 May (Box 38 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 1)
  - Unidentified, Photographs, 1956; 1969; 2000; Undated (Box 38 (8-Photographs and Scrapbooks), Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1970-1973; 1977-1978 (Oversized 4)
  - Albany Elected School Board, Collage, 1971 (Oversized Flat File 1)
- Memorabilia, 1992-2001; 9; 0.5 cubic ft.
  Memorabilia consists of awards given to the organization, LWVAC stationary, a tea set, license plate cover, and buttons.
  Arranged alphabetically by format
  - Awards, 1992-2001 (Box 38 (9-Memorabilia), Folder 3)
  - Stationery, Undated (Box 38 (9-Memorabilia), Folder 4)
  - Tea Set, Undated (Oversized 5)
  - LWV License Plate Cover, Undated (Oversized 5)
  - LWV Buttons, Undated (Oversized 5)
- Audio-Visual Material, 1983-2001; 10; 1 cubic foot
  This series is made up of videocassettes, audio cassettes and one CD-ROM. The LWVAC sponsored a Health Care Town Forum in 1983 and 1994, a Health Care Town Meeting in 1991, and a Power the Vote Town Meeting in 1996. Each of these was recorded on video. Other VHS tapes contain information relating to the League of Women Voters Education Fund Projects and projects of other local Leagues. Also on VHS and audiotape is the LWVAC History Night held on November 11, 1993. There are several interviews on audio cassettes from a LWVAC oral history project as part of the League's History Night. The oral history and History Night tapes feature members discussing their childhoods, how they became members of the League, and issues in which they were involved. The episode of WAMC's Vox Pop features a discussion with Becky Cain, president of the League of Women Voters, about politics and Albany politics. The audiotape of George Swiers includes a speech he gave at an unidentified event followed by a question and answer session in which he discusses diversity, the legislative process, and related issues. The CD-ROM disc contains a Power Point presentation, "Costs of Urban Sprawl", an education campaign done by the LWV of Buffalo/Niagara in 2001.
  Arranged by format
  - 75 Years of a Great Idea, 0:18, Undated (Vhs 1)
  - Albany County Health Care Forum, labeled October 28, Undated (Vhs 2)
  - The Constitution and the Courts, 1987 May 24 (Vhs 3)
  - Educate for the Environment's Sake, New Castle League of Women Voters, 0:20, 1991 May 24 (Vhs 4)
  - Health Care Forum, 1983 September 28 (Vhs 5)
  - Health Care Town Forum, 1994 May 30 (Vhs 6)
  - History Night, League of Women Voters Albany County, 1993 November 11 (Vhs 7)
  - The Last Days of Maplewood, Sponsored by the Maplewood League of Women Voters, Maplewood, N.J., 0:16.48, Undated (Vhs 8)
    Discussion Guide available.
  - Overview of Health Care Services Albany County, 1:28, Undated (Vhs 9)
  - Solid Waste in the Capital District, 1989 Spring (Vhs 10)
  - Power the Vote, 1996 October 6 (Vhs 11)
  - Power the Vote, 1996 October 1 (Vhs 12)
  - Power the Vote Town Meeting, 1996 October 6 (Vhs 13)
  - Town Meeting on Health Care, 1991 November 19 (Vhs 14)
  - Tools for Drinking Water Protection, 1:30, 1997 March 19 (Vhs 15)
    Leader's Guide available.
  - Town Meeting on Health Care, Albany, N.Y., 1991 September 19 (Vhs 16)
  - U.S. Third World Policy, Undated (Vhs 17)
  - Catskill Concert of Early Music, Undated (Cassette 1)
  - History Night, 1993 November 11 (Cassette 2)
  - History Night, 1993 November 11 (Cassette 3)
  - Donovan, Hope, 1993 November (Cassette 4)
  - Axelrod, Selma, 1993 November (Cassette 5)
  - Dorkin, Natalie, Undated (Cassette 6)
  - Dorkin, Natalie, Undated (Cassette 7)
  - Hawkins, Betty, Undated (Cassette 8)
  - Hawkins, Betty, Undated (Cassette 9)
  - Swiers, George, 1998 September 24 (Cassette 10)
  - Vox Pop, 1997 May 12 (Cassette 11)
  - "Costs of Urban Sprawl", an Education Campaign by the LWV of Buffalo/Niagara, 2001 (Cd 1)
    Brochure available.
  - Supporting Material, ca. 1997-2001 (Box 39 (10-Audio-Visual Material), Folder 1)
    - The Last Days of Maplewood, Sponsored by the Maplewood League of Women Voters, Maplewood, N.J., Discussion Guide, undated
    - Tools for Drinking Water Protection, Leader's Guide and Correspondence, March 19, 1997
    - "Costs of Urban Sprawl", an Education Campaign by the League of Women Voters of Buffalo/Niagara, Brochure, 2001.